Jun-Quan LIM

Mobile: +65 81238021

Email: junquan.lim@u.nus.edu Skype: live:e3d8872650aa49fe

GitHub: JunQuann

Online Resume: https://junquann.github.io/



Personal Statement

About Me

My high school motto, "Nil Sine Labore" is an expression that I identify with and it is deeply embedded in my values and principles. Translated it directly, it says "Nothing without labor"; and till this day, everything that I have achieved in my life stems from my willingness to grind deeper and work harder than most people would.

Fast forward a few years, I am currently a sophomore in National University of Singapore (NUS) School of Computing majoring in Computer Science. On top of pursuing academic excellence, I am actively involved in hostel activities as well. Being the Sports Director of my hostel, I was given the opportunity to serve the community that I have come to know and love. In order to broaden my perspectives, I engaged in activities outside my comfort zone such as dancing, singing and soccer. I believe that these experiences from differing backgrounds will enhance my ability to empathize with more situations.

Work Experiences

From September 2017 till December 2017, I worked in a start-up called SUP. It was an enriching experience as I was able to immerse in the start-up culture in Singapore. As the start-up was selected for an accelerator program, I had the opportunity to work in shared spaces with several other start-ups and also participate in weekly networking sessions with local investors.

Why I can contribute

[] Clear Communication: Being the of Sports Director in hall has taught me a great deal about communication. With 30 sports and an entire sports committee under my care, I had to make sure that I could communicate ideas and instructions clearly to prevent any confusion. On top of that, mediating conflicts through effective communication is essential to ensure harmony amongst the sports scene.

[] <u>Grit and Passion</u>: Having academic responsibilities and hostel commitments did not stop me from pursuing a part-time internship which I was passionate about. Though there were times where it was really hard to cope, I dug deep and continued to excel in all fronts; which I would say in soccer terms, achieving the 'treble'.

| Versatility: Though I started working in the start-up as a software engineer intern, that did not stop me from going out to the streets with my fellow marketing team to collect some survey results from strangers. I learnt several essential 'start-up skills' such as growth hacking and competitive analysis from different members of the team.

[Optimism and Growth Mindset: My bubbly character always points me towards the direction of possibilities. Whenever I hit a rock, I will find a way to overcome it. I enjoy the grind and the process where I learn and become better at something, and this has helped me overcome several obstacles in life.

Having worked in a start-up before, I understand the micro-cycles and fast pace nature of its operation. I enjoy the start-up culture where we can sit across the dining table, talking about the endless possibilities that can ensue from our efforts; and I hope that you can give me this opportunity to get excited about your dreams together.

Work Experience

May 2018 - Aug 2018 **KASISTO** Quality Assurance Engineer Intern Evaluate, Propose and Deploy initial suite of true functional test cases Explore popular testing tools in the market (Postman) Propose test case management approach/tooling Creation of live chat web hook mock and test cases Basic troubleshooting and content management tasks Sep 2017 - Dec 2017 SUP Singapore Software Engineer Intern Maintained a web application chat bot in Django framework Extended chat bot to other regions by deploying additional instances using AWS EC2 Implemented black-box services for the company's application using Sendgrid and Nexmo Made HTTPs post requests with JSON to update databases Implemented image-upload service with AWS S3 buckets and python Engaged in marketing surveys and crafted summary reports Jan 2016 - Jul 2016 **Freelance Tutor** Singapore Taught up to 8 private students and employed at 3 different tuition centres Managed the workload of students and tracked their progress Formulated teaching resources to aid learning of students Sep 2014 - Dec 2015 National Service (SAF) Singapore Instructor In charge of media coverage for activities and the knowledge of all cadets Expedited the transition from traditional pedagogy to a more technological-savvy one by creating a simple web application for educational purposes Appointed as the vice-chairperson for the Anniversary event where I had to coordinate with multiple vendors as well as negotiate for suitable pricing during the planning phase Leadership/Extracurricular Activities Apr 2017 - Apr 2018 Sports Director (External) for Hostel Singapore Oversaw the operation of 30 sports and Sports Management Board (SMB) Restructured SMB by attaching a team manager to each sport in order to provide more support to the teams Actively discussed the overall direction of the hall and implemented policies for improvements Organized Inter-Hall Games (IHG) for 30 sports which had over 900 participants. **Overseas Student Volunteer** Sep 2016 - May 2017 Singapore Collaborated with local villagers to build community hall from scratch Planted 1000 cashew apple plants for villagers Built an incinerator in school for proper disposal of rubbish Educated students on importance of environmental preservations through games

Education

Aug 2016 - Present National University of Singapore Singapore

Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Science

(Course details in Appendix A)

Jan 2011 - Dec 2012Victoria Junior CollegeSingapore

• Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level

• Pursued a science course and attained 4 H2 Distinctions.

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java Python C C++ Shell Scripting	Proficient Intermediate Basic Basic Basic
Web	HTML, CSS Bootstrap PHP	Proficient Intermediate Intermediate
Database	SQL PostgreSQL	Intermediate Intermediate
Scripting	JavaScript JSON	Intermediate Basic
Markup	XML	Basic
Server Management & Network	Computer Network Programming	Basic
Operating Systems	Windows Unix/BSD	Basic Basic
AWS	EC2 S3	Basic Basic
Multimedia	GIMP	Basic

Language Proficiency

SpokenEnglish – fluent; Mandarin – fluentWrittenEnglish – competent; Chinese – average

Additional Information

As my family is financially challenged, I understood the importance of financial literacy from a young age. I read up on several books about investing and financial management to ensure that I can attain financial stability in the future. As such, I started investing since the age of 18 from the stipends I received while serving national service. I follow financial news closely to ensure that I am updated so as to make better investing decisions.

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.50 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2016	Year 1/Semester 1	Quantitative Reasoning	А
		Discrete Structures	B+
		Calculus for Computing	B+
		Programming Methodology	CS
		Real Estate Investments and Trusts Laws	CS
Jan – May 2017	Year 1/Semester 2	Linear Algebra	А
		IS Innovations in Organization and Society	А
		Computer Organization	A-
		Data Structures and Algorithms, I	CS
		English for Academic Purpose	CS
Jun – Jul 2017	Year 2/Special Term 2	Data Structures and Algorithms, II	A-
Aug – Nov 2017	Year 2/Semester 1	Software Engineering #	А
		Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	A-
		Introduction to Computer Networks	B+
		Design and Analysis of Algorithms	B+
		Asking Questions	CU
Jan – May 2018	Year 2/Semester 2	Introduction to Artificial Intelligence	IP
		Database Systems	IP
		Probability and Statistics	IP
		Understanding Body, Mind and Culture through Sports	IP
		Asking Questions	IP

The **Software Engineering** module focuses on teaching students the fundamentals of software engineering principles. This module is the first exposure into software development in the curriculum. It teaches basics GitHub and workflow management within a team. Students are required to add additional features to an existing codebase. The existing codebase is an address-book. Students are to think through their target audience and their user stories so that the features implemented are well targeted. Each added feature has to come with automated testing to ensure that there is a smooth integration. On top of this, students have to craft user guides and developer guides which are part of the grading. This is to ensure that students understand the importance of a clear set of instructions for either the users or the developers.

Project Portfolio: https://cs2103aug2017-w14-b3.github.io/main/team/JunQuann.html

NUS Grading Scale:

 $A+ \& \ A \ (5.0); \ A- \ (4.5); \ B+ \ (4.0); \ B \ (3.5); \ B- \ (3.0); \ C+ \ (2.5); \ C \ (2.0); \ D+ \ (1.5); \ D \ (1.0); \ F \ (0)$

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn